Guide to the Franz & Sally Hughes Schrader Diaries
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Franz & Sally Hughes Schrader Diaries,
1913-1970
Schrader, Franz, 1891-1962.
3 linear ft. (51 items in 6 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library,
4079313
Biographical Note
Franz Schrader was professor of zoology at Columbia University, 1930-1959. His wife, Sally Hughes Schrader (1895- ) was professor of zoology at Duke University, 1962-1966.
Scope and Content
A collection of diaries (49 vols.) kept by Franz Schrader and his wife, Sally Hughes Schrader. Much of the material relates to academic life in general, the Dept. of Zoology at Columbia University, and field trips made by the Schraders to Mexico, Guatemala, and British Honduras. Also, Franz Schrader's angling diary, 1906-1971.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 1 series:
Diaries
Subjects
Duke University.--Zoology Dept.; Columbia University.--Dept. of Zoology.; Schrader, Sally Hughes, b. 1895.; Women scientists.; Zoology--Fieldwork--Mexico.; Zoology--Fieldwork--Guatemala.; Zoology--Fieldwork--Belize.; Women college teachers--North Carolina--Durham.; Fishing.; Women--Diaries.; Universities and colleges--New York (State)--New York.; Universities and colleges--North Carolina--Durham.; Diaries.; College teachers.; Zoologists.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
1972 M-72 Schrader, Sally Hughes Gift
03/17/1993 M-93-03-17 Literary note Duke University Gift
Gift of Sally Hughes Schrader, 1972.
Gift of Duke University, 1993.
- Diaries
  A collection of diaries (49 vols.) kept by Franz Schrader and his wife, Sally Hughes Schrader. Much of the material relates to academic life in general, the Dept. of Zoology at Columbia University, and field trips made by the Schraders to Mexico, Guatemala, and British Honduras. Also, Franz Schrader's angling diary, 1906-1971.2
  - Volume 1, February 1927 - June 1927, () (Box 1)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9010]
  - Volume 2, 12 June 1927 - 1 April 1928, () (Box 1)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9010 ]
  - Volume 3, 3 April 1928 - 30 December 1928, () (Box 1)
  - Volume 4, 30 December 1928 - 1 May 1929, () (Box 1)
    [On microfilm MN# 90-9011]
  - Volume 5, 1 May 1929 - 23 March 1930, () (Box 1)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9011]
  - Volume 6, 24 March 1930 - 20 April 1931, () (Box 1)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9012]
  - Volume 7, 21 April 1931 - 16 March 1932, () (Box 1)
  - Volume 8, 17 March 1932 - 21 January 1933, () (Box 1)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9012 & 98-9013]
  - Volume 9, 21 January 1933 - 29 September 1933, () (Box 1)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9013]
  - Volume 10, Fall 1933, () (Box 1)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9013 & 98-9014]
  - Volume 11, 1 January 1934 - 20 February 1935, () (Box 2)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9014]
  - Volume 12, 22 February 1935 - 23 December 1935, () (Box 2)
  - Volume 13, 28 December 1935 - 7 February 1937, () (Box 2)
  - Volume 14, 9 February 1937 - 10 September 1937, () (Box 2)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9015]
  - Volume 15, 11 September 1937 - 31 August 1938, () (Box 2)
  - Volume 16, 1 Sept 1938 - 26 June 1939, () (Box 2)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9015 & 98-9016]
  - Volume 17, 27 June 1939 - 25 May 1940, () (Box 2)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9016]
  - Volume 18, 26 May 1940 - 3 March 1941, () (Box 2)
  - Volume 19, 4 March 1941 - 9 November 1941, () (Box 2)
  - Volume 20, 10 November 1941 - 19 July 1942, () (Box 2)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9017]
  - Volume 21, 20 July 1942 - 4 June 1943, () (Box 2)
  - Volume 22, 5 June 1943 - 29 January 1944, () (Box 2)
  - Volume 23, 30 January 1944 - 2 May 1944, () (Box 3)
    [On microfilm MN# 2000-1219]
  - Volume 24, 3 June 1944 - 13 March 1945, () (Box 3)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9023]
  - Volume 25, 14 March 1945 - 13 March 1946, () (Box 3)
  - Volume 26, 14 March 1946 - 30 June 1947, () (Box 3)
  - Volume 27, 1 July 1947 - 20 December 1948, () (Box 3)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9024]
  - Volume 28, 22 December 1948 - 12 November 1949, () (Box 3)
    [On microfilm MN# 90-9024]
  - Volume 29, 13 November 1949 - 21 October 1950, () (Box 3)
  - Volume 30, 22 October 1950 - 4 October 1951, () (Box 3)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9025]
  - Volume 31, 5 October 1951 - 15 July 1952, () (Box 3)
  - Volume 32, 16 July 1952 - January 15 1953, () (Box 3)
  - Volume 33, 18 January 1953 - 24 August 1953, () (Box 4)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9026]
  - Volume 34, 24 August 1953 - 14 April 1954, () (Box 4)
  - Volume 35, 15 April 1954 - 3 December 1954, () (Box 4)
  - Volume 36, 4 December 1954 - 4 August 1955, () (Box 4)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9027]
  - Volume 37, 5 August 1955 - 18 June 1956, () (Box 4)
  - Volume 38, 19 June 1956 - 22 May 1957, () (Box 4)
  - Volume 39, 23 May 1957 - 17 April 1958, () (Box 4)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9028]
  - Volume 40, 18 April 1958 - 1 Febuary 1959, () (Box 4)
  - Volume 41, February 1959 - 8 August 1959, () (Box 4)
  - Volume 42, 9 August 1959 - 2 August 1960, () (Box 4)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9029]
  - Volume 43, 3 August 1960 - 9 August 1961, () (Box 4)
  - Volume 44, 10 August 1961 - 23 August 1962, () (Box 4)
  - Volume 45, 24 August 1962 - 19 August 1963, () (Box 5)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9030]
  - Volume 46, 20 August 1963 - 23 September 1964, () (Box 5)
  - Volume 47, 24 September 1964 - 4 January 1944, () (Box 5)
  - Volume 48, 6 January 1966 - 3 July 1967, () (Box 5)
    [On microfilm MN# 98-9031]
  - Volume 49, 16 August 1967 - 18 October 1970, () (Box 5)
  - Fishing Diary, 1906-1971, () (Box 6)
    [On microfilm MN# Not on microfilm]